# CARRICULUM VITAE (CV) HEZRON MURITHI JOSEPH

Mobile No: 0740302808/0701354886 Email Address: <u>jeihezmurithi@gmail.com</u>

determined to achieve as we help others. A strict observer of time.

environment for personal development.

LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/ hezron-murithi-71110a246

GitHub github.com/MUTIJ

#### Personal Details

Nationality: Kenyan

# Career profile.

> To work in a dynamic performance-based organization that offers prospects for career growth and advancement while at the same time create an enabling

I am an Intelligent and hardworking Software Developer with a background of 2 year experience in software development and ICT support. Highly educated and committed to creating dynamic apps for the android environment. Extensive knowledge in Software Development Life Cycle (SDLC), Agile methodologies and Quality product development. I have ability to work under conducive environment with minimum supervision, Willingness to learn more and being

#### General Objectives

- > To develop myself into becoming one of the most respectable professionals in my field of work.
- > To seek a challenging position to meet my competencies, capabilities, skills, education and experience in providing outstanding performance.
- > Effective Collaborator.
- > Strong Problem-solving Abilities.
- > Precision and Attention to Detail.
- > Outstanding Communication Skills.
- > Skilled System administrator.
- Proficient in Programming Languages: Flutter Dart, Java, HTML CSS and PHP, Mobile apps, react, AngularJs, angular, Spring boot.
- > Web application development.
- > Proficient in Android and iOS development.
- MySQL
- > Object-oriented programming.
- ➤ Good in Version Control (Git, GitHub).
- > Good in Cloud Computing (firebase).
- > General IT Support.

## Skills

#### **Experience**

# Tangazoletu limited (Software Developer). (January 2023– current)

# **Responsibilities:**

- ➤ Performed root cause analysis (RCAs) in order to identify breakdowns in processes and systems that contributed to downtimes and how to prevent future events
- ➤ Identifying technical problems and developing software updates and fixes.
- > Created custom USSD journeys for different Saccos based on their requirements.
- ➤ Working as part of the team involved in in high complexity source code development.
- > Part of the team that rolled out new features for our customers.
- > Optimized Mobile Apps to utilize easily customizable JSON powered forms(Formly Forms) for easy maintainability for the many clients with a variety of requirements.
- Collaborated with the team in developing new system end to end.

# Mpsha Hospital(ICT Support) (January 2024 – February 2014).

# **Responsibilities:**

- Networking
- > Server maintenance.
- Cable managements.
- General ICT support based on the employees request.

# Dalima Tech Company.

Nairobi, Kenya | Aug 2022 - Jan 2023

- Writing lines of code, testing and debugging software, learning computer languages in a realistic setting, and functioning as part of a team.
- Delivered complex communications, driving implementations and other high visibility growth projects.
- Applied strong writing, editing and proofreading abilities to each assignment to produce best possible content.
- Coordinated testing activities along with project managers and developers.
- Prepared news stories based on information provided by assignment desk and press releases.
- Attended team meetings to discuss projects, brainstorm ideas and put forward solutions to issues.

#### UNIVERSITY EDUCATION.

University attended: St Paul's university.

Duration: September 2020 – 2024

Course taking: Bachelor of Science in Computer Science.

# **Certifications and Training.**

Training attended: ACWICT

Course taken: Web Application Development, Digital Entrepreneurship and group

formation and team work

Certification: Skills for Improved Jobs and Livelihood.

#### **Academic Qualifications**

College attended: Microsoft IT academy. Duration taken: May 2023 – August 2023.

Course taken: Dart Programming.

Certification: Dart application development certificate.

Workshop Attended: Lets Upgrade

Course taken: Postman API Fundamentals

Certification: Postman API Fundamentals Student Expert

Verification code: LUEPAFSOCT12317

Workshop Attended: Lets Upgrade

Course taken: DBMS & MySQL Zero to Hero Certification: DBMS and SQL Zero to Hero Verification code: LUEDBSQLNOV123204

Workshop Attended: DevTown

Course taken: Frontend Web development with React.js and JavaScript

Certification: Frontend Web development with React.js and JavaScript Verification

code: https://cert.devtown.in/verify/Z2je7Gs

#### HIGH SCHOOL EDUCATION.

School attended: Burieruri Boys' High School.

Duration: February 2015 - November 2019. Certification:

High school certificate.

#### PRIMARY SCHOOL EDUCATION.

School attended: Kaoronene primary School.

Duration: 2007 - 2015.

Certification: Primary school certificate.

- Travelling and hiking
- Quantum Physics
- Robotics
- Doing research

#### Interest